http://www.sportmedbc.com/content/privacy-policy

Skip to main content
About SportMedBCAbout SportMedBCVision & MissionHistoryGovernanceOpportunitiesMembershipProgramsProgramsSportMed RunWalkSportMed RunWalk2020 LearnToRun10K Fall Program2021 InTraining Program2021 InTraining ProgramClinic Locations & DatesClinic CoordinatorsInTraining LeadersCorporate Clinics Frequently Asked Questions10K to Half Marathon ProgramAboriginal RunWalkAboriginal RunWalkHealthBeatOnline InTrainingNordic WalkingSportMed SafetySportMed SafetyEvent Medical ServicesCourses & WorkshopsCourses & WorkshopsSports First Aid CoursesAthletic Taping CoursesConcussion WorkshopsSportSmart WorkshopsConcussion InformationConcussion InformationGeneral InformationConcussion ManagementConcussion Management WorkshopsConcussion Resources & LinksHeadCheck HealthBC Sports Aid ProgramSportMed PerformanceSportMed PerformanceIntegrated Performance System & Team BCRBC GRANFONDO WHISTLER TRAINING CLINICSInTraining Triathlon ClinicsNewsPractitioners & ClinicsPractitioners & ClinicsBC PractitionersBC ClinicsResource LibraryShopCourse Calendar Login or Create AccountContact
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
SportMedBC is committed to protecting the privacy of individuals whose personal information is collected and held in our databases or as a necessary part of registering to participate in our programs or to receive services. As part of our commitment to you, we want to clarify why we may ask for your personal information. The Personal Information Act of British Columbia (“the Act”) regulates the way in which private sector organizations within British Columbia collect, use, keep, secure and disclose personal information. “Personal Information” means all information about an identifiable individual. Our Need for Personal Information SportMedBC collects personal information for the following reasons:
to efficiently and appropriately service the needs of members and subscribers; to deliver the services and programs that you request or register to receive; to ensure the efficient operation of any conferences, workshops and training camps that we may organize; to carry out duties as assumed when undertaking to provide medical coverage for sporting events; to provide some assurance to sporting and other organizations those persons representing themselves as SportMedBC “SportsAiders” have received the appropriate level of training and are currently accredited. This information enables SportMedBC to act as an intermediary organizing medical coverage for sporting events;
to promote the services of sport medicine and sport science practitioners (via our online Directory).
We may also collect and use your information, in anonymous form, for statistical purposes regarding internal or external issues of mutual interest to promote and further the interests of the practice of sport medicine and sport science. Collection, Use and Disclosure of Personal Information Where practical, we endeavour to collect personal information directly from the person to whom the information pertains. If necessary, we may collect personal information from other sources. If you are an individual to whom the Act applies, by asking SportMedBC to provide services to you, you consent to our necessary collection, use or disclosure of your personal information in order to properly provide the requested services to you. It is our policy to collect personal information about individuals in accordance with the provisions of the Act. In general, we will try to get your explicit consent to use or disclose your personal information. The Act deems that an individual has consented to our collection, use or disclosure of personal information about that individual if, at the time the consent is deemed to be given, the purpose would be considered obvious to a reasonable person. In such circumstances, we may collect, use or disclose personal information without obtaining a written or verbal consent to do so. However, we will never give out your contact information or other sensitive information about you without your express consent, unless we are obligated to do so by law. The Act also permits us to collect, use or disclose personal information about an individual in some circumstances without the individual’s consent. Those include (but are not limited to) circumstances in which:
the collection, use or disclosure is clearly in the interests of the individual and consent cannot be obtained in a timely way; it is reasonable to expect that the collection or use of personal information with the consent of the individual would compromise the availability or accuracy of the information, and the collection or use of the information is necessary for an investigation or proceeding; it is reasonable to expect that the disclosure of personal information with the consent of the individual would compromise an investigation or proceeding, and the disclosure of the information is necessary for an investigation or proceeding;
the personal information is available to the public from a prescribed source; the collection, use or disclosure of personal information is required or authorized by law.
When we collect, use or disclose personal information, we will make reasonable efforts to ensure that it is accurate and complete. If your personal information changes, we ask that you notify us as soon as possible so that we may keep our records up to date. You may withdraw your consent to our collection, use or disclosure of your personal information at any time, by giving us notice in writing at the address set out below. Security of Personal Information We recognize our legal obligations to protect the confidential information of our members, subscribers, clients, program participants, and others who provide us with their personal information. We have therefore made arrangements to secure the data against the unauthorized access, collection, use, disclosure, copying, modification, disposal or destruction of personal information. Requests for Access to Personal InformationThe Act permits individuals to submit written requests to us to provide them with: their personal information under our custody or control; information about how their personal information under our control has been and is being used by us; the names of the individuals and organizations to whom their personal information under our control has been disclosed by us.
We will respond to requests in the time allowed by the Act and will make a reasonable effort to assist applicants and to respond as accurately and completely as reasonably possible. All requests may be subject to any fees and disbursements the law permits us to charge.An individual’s ability to access his or her personal information under our control is not absolute. The Act provides that we must not disclose personal information when:
the disclosure could reasonably be expected to threaten the safety or physical or mental health of an individual other than the individual who made the request; he disclosure can reasonably be expected to cause immediate or grave harm to the safety or to the physical or mental health of the individual who made the request; the disclosure would reveal personal information about another individual;
the disclosure would reveal the identity of an individual who has provided personal information about another individual and the individual providing the personal information does not consent to disclosure of his or her identity.
The Act further provides that we are not required to disclose personal information when:
the personal information is protected by solicitor-client privilege;
the disclosure of the personal information would reveal confidential commercial information that, if disclosed, could, in the opinion of a reasonable person, harm the competitive position of an organization; the personal information was collected without consent for the purposes of an investigation, and the investigation and associated proceedings and appeals have not been completed;
the personal information was collected or created by a mediator or arbitrator in the conduct of a mediation or arbitration for which he or she was appointed to act: (i) under a collective agreement; (ii) under an enactment, or (iii) by a court.
Requests for Correction of Personal Information The law permits individuals to submit written requests to us to correct errors or omissions in their personal information that is in our custody or control. We will:
correct the personal information and, if reasonable to do so, send correction notifications to any other organizations to whom we disclosed the incorrect information; or decide not to correct the personal information, but annotate the personal information that a correction was requested but not made.
Contacting or Communicating With Us If you have any questions with respect to our policies concerning the handling of your personal information, or if you wish to request access to, or correction of, your personal information under our care and control, please contact our Privacy Officer at: SportMedBC 2350 - 3713 Kensington Avenue, Burnaby, BC V5B 0A7 Telephone: 604.294.3050  •  Fax: 604.294.3020 If you are dissatisfied with our handling of your personal information, we invite you to contact our Privacy Officer in writing, setting out the reasons for your concern. If, after our Privacy Officer has reviewed and responded to your concern, you remain dissatisfied, you may wish to contact the Office of the Information and Privacy Commissioner at: P.O. Box 9038, Stn Prov Govt, Victoria, BC V8W 9A4 Telephone (250) 387-5629 •  Fax (250) 387-1696
Resource LibraryLearn More
Find a PractitionerUse our search to find a SportMedBC Health PractitionerFind a Practitioner
Get more out of SportMedBC!Create Account
Latest News
10 Dec 2020
InTraining Program Start Date Postponed to February 27, 2021
In light of the PHO’s announcement on Monday December 7th to extend province...
Read More
9 Dec 2020
DECEMBER 3, 2020: UPDATES TO PROVINCE-WIDE RESTRICTIONS
As of December 3, 2020, there have been further updates to the restrictions for sport...
Read More
More to do at SportMedBC...
